# IVAN PILO SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

# CURRICULUM VITAE

About me and my experience





#### Portfolio

ipilo.github.io/ivanpilo.com

behance.net/ivanpilo

dribbble.com/ivanpilo



66

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE



#### Contact me

· Mail

ivanpilo@protonmail.com

· Phone:

+44 0734 1947 182

I understand what makes an experience good or bad. I think through user problems, find realistic, practical solutions, mock them up in detail, and work with designers and developers to ship them.

I have an appreciation of good design as well as a deep understanding of composition, balance, symmetry, and white space.

I like to solve problems in unusual and innovative ways.

I love to contribute to the definition of a product's design language and experience.

"



#### Tools

















Premiere Pro

Ae After Effects

After Photo

★★★★ Video



### Languages

English fluentFrench fluentSpanish native

· Catalan native

## Objectives

- · To be part of a company that will allow me to grow professionally, and where I can put into practice my experience and way of working.
- To develop ambitious projects with which I can broaden my portfolio and my career path.
- · To work with a respectful company, in a pleasant atmosphere where each person enjoys their job.



### Why me?

- · I truly enjoy design and all its aspects, I feel great interest in the way design can communicate.
- · I take every new project as a personal challenge, where originality and effectiveness are my main tools.

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

- Degree in Audiovisual&Multimedia
  Universitat de Girona (ERAM/UDG) 2005 2009
- Master of Arts in Film Editing
  Escuela de Cine de Barcelona (ECIB) 2006 -2007
- Studies of Engineering in Computer Science
  Universitat de Girona (UDG) 2001 2004
- · Studies of Psychology
  UNED (ongoing)

#### **COMPLEMENTARY COURSES**

- Communication Strategies
   Universitat de Girona (UDG) 2010
- Design Thinking&Innovation
   Escola AURA 2017
- Manual Printing Type
   Escola de Disseny (EDI) 2016

## CAREER SUMMARY

- The Cambium Group (2019-present)
   As a lead product designer I've worked on implementing new features, redesigning or improving user interfaces and user journeys, conceptualizing new ideas for the group and bringing to life new products.
- EF Education First (2017-2019)

  I was responsible for producing and maintaining the online branding, design & UX guide that influences all EF divisions and markets. I was also responsible for all centrally managed web projects which are shared across all EF divisions.
- · Freelance (2011-2017)

I collaborated with developer teams & managed a wide variety of cross-media projects involving branding, illustrations & UI design for startups and companies such as 7digital, Onkyo, Entertainmentnews, Technics, Snowite and radioplayer worldwide.

- Iglésies Associats (2009-2011)

  Creation of graphic identities for different companies.
- Baby Kids Dreams (2004-2009)

  Production file development such as stamping tasks for different clients in the fashion industry.

### **66** Motivation

"Design must seduce, shape, and more importantly evoke an emotional response"

"Simplicity is the ultimate form of sophistication"

"Designers are meant to be loved, not to be understood"

"The essential part of creativity is not being afraid to fail"